## AYUK, ROLAND OJONG

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A good Full-Stack Developer/Software Developer with experience in development of web applications. I have exceled in every stage in software development life cycle, including coding, debugging, testing and maintenance. Very good in devising innovative and tailored solutions to assist businesses achieve their goals in a variety of industries. Great skills and knowledge of leading programming tools with a strong background in mathematics, algorithms and data processing logic. While developing softwares, I focus more on Security, Performance and Media Responsiveness.

### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Excellent Project Management Skills
- Strong knowledge in Programming Language( JavaScript and Python)
- Strong Communication and Excellent Interpersonal Skill
- Fast pace learner
- Knowledge of Information Security Solutions
- Great Communication and Presentation Skills

#### SKILLS / FRAMEWORKS

**FRONTEND TECHNOLOGIES:** React.js, Next.js, Redux, Typescript, Material UI, Styled-Components, Netlify, Varcel, React-Testing-Library and Cypress.

**BACKEND TECHNOLOGIES:** Node.js(express.js), REST API, Golang, Heroku and Digital Ocean.

**DATABASES:** MongoDB, MySQL and PosgresQL.

**VERSION CONTROL & CI/CD:** Git, Github and Github Actions

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Successfully been one of the core developers who built wowcatholic.com
- Won 5 times Developer of the Month at WOCA Group LTD
- Developed 3 personal projects, Expenses Tracker, video chat and Track Money(in progress)

.

#### PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

# WOCA GROUP LTD FULL-STACK DEVELOPER Key Duties:

2021 - Present

- Im
  - Improving existing features of the product and working on new features as the applications continue to scale
  - Ensuring code quality and standards while meeting deadlines and delivering targets set by the product team.
  - Working closely with product managers and data analysts to improve the overall product, the design team to improve the user experience, and the front-end team for design implementation

# **HP Technical LTD FRONT-END DEVELOPER Key Duties:**

2019 -2021

- Working closely with product managers to implement new features according to well-defined specifications
- Refactoring and improving existing features of the product based on best practices, changing requirements and feedback from QA
- Writing Component and e2e Tests to ensure code robustness and documentation.
- Exchanging ideas with the design team to improve the user experience.
- Reviewing your peers' code to keep our code base clean and extensible.

### **PROJECTS**

• Wowcatholic.com: www.wowcatholic.com

• Expense Tracker: www.roland-expense-tracker.netlify.app

• Video Chat Web App: www.roland-video-app.netlify.app

### **TRAININGS**

• AWS CLOUD PRACTIONER

2021

• Certified Ethical Hacking (CEH)

2020

## **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

• B.Sc. Computer Science (Second Class Upper Division (Hons))
West African Senior School Certificate Examination,

2009-2013 2004-2008.

	_	_			
$\mathbf{n}$					
ж			/		/
$\mathbf{D}$	<b>\</b> ,	-1/		ш.	

Spoken Languages: English (Fluent)